<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Generated on 2022-12-28T11:15:41Z. -->
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
         xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
   <rdf:Description>
      <dc:title>A Bisayan Grammar and Notes on Bisayan Rhetoric and Poetics and Filipino Dialectology</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Norberto Romuáldez y López (1875–1941)</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Project Gutenberg, Urbana, Illinois, USA., 2022-12-22</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2022-12-22</dc:date>
      <dc:rights>This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere at no cost and with almost no restrictions whatsoever. You may copy it, give it away or re-use it under the terms of the Project Gutenberg License included with this eBook or online at www.gutenberg.org.
This eBook is produced by the Online Distributed Proofreading Team at www.pgdp.net.
Waray-waray is one of several languages called Visayan or Bisayan, and is spoken in the eastern part of the Visayas region of the Philippines, that is, the islands of Leyte and Samar, by, currently, about 2 to 3 million speakers. This book is a grammar of the language by the (locally) well-known literator Norberto Romuáldez. This book is quite scarce, and was apparently printed using rather primitive equipment on cheap paper in the Philippines.
The author followed the Spanish-based orthography of Waray-waray (back in 1908, when the Philippines had been American territory for a decade), but was quite aware of spelling-issues, as shown in this work.
Scans for this book are available from the Internet Archive (copy 
1).

</dc:rights>
      <dc:subject>Waray language -- Grammar</dc:subject>
      <dc:description>Waray-waray is one of several languages called Visayan or Bisayan, and is spoken in the eastern part of the Visayas region of the Philippines, that is, the islands of Leyte and Samar, by, currently, about 2 to 3 million speakers. This book is a grammar of the language by the (locally) well-known literator Norberto Romuáldez.</dc:description>
      <dc:identifier>pg:69603</dc:identifier>
   </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
